Great to be back. Thanks for the
invitation.
>> you're everywhere. I see you everywhere.
It's crazy. And people are loving you on
Manneckt apparently cuz I see you
everyday you're getting Manneckts.
People are asking the questions on
You're actually getting back to people.
>> time. Oh yeah. And you know, I looked at
the Manneckt the other day I'm like,
"Why am I not in the super heavyweight
yet?"
>> [laughter]
>> You're close though to super
heavyweight, no? Are you almost there?
Yeah.
>> I am.
>> Cuz you're first place in the
heavyweight right now. So, we have the
heavyweight champion in the house right
now. So, I got a lot of things I want to
talk to you about. I you know,
especially with recent stories with SPLC
that you saw that story broke. I'm
curious to know what you think about
that. The FISA thing which is like hey
>> Oh yeah.
>> Nixon-Carter we thought we going to get
away but now we're kind of like, "Well,
let's keep it." I want to know why you
think we're doing that. What the motives
are. I have my own ideas of why I think
we're doing it. I want to know what you
think about it.
And then
you said something about the vault which
was like, "What is this vault?" What was
it called? Vault 17 or Vault
>> Vault 7. Vault 7. I want to hear about
Vault 7. And a few other things with the
scientists. You saw the whole scientist
where
>> Yeah. Some of them disappeared.
disappearing, suicide, you know, or you
know,
missing or who knows? Like you can't
find these guys four of them being from
NASA. Mhm. And then the JPL the other
four were from nuclear fusion and weapon
and then three are apparently high
clearance security. Not really a direct
contact. One of them recently David
Wilcox
who said he wasn't going to commit
suicide in 2022 in a tweet apparently
just
took his own life which is pretty wild.
But I want to get into one thing right
off the bat.
You were on a podcast and my phone
started blowing up.
>> [laughter]
>> And I'm like, "Why is everybody texting
me this? Look what John said about you."
What did I say?
>> "John is about to get on the podcast."
So, Rob, if you have the clip, I want to
start off with this. I want to address
it one by one by one. I want you to
cover this for me. So, you're on a
podcast. I don't know which podcast this
is.
But whatever it is I was texted by
everybody with this. So, go ahead and
play this clip. I was watching Patrick
Bet-David yesterday. And Patrick is a
a hardcore Zionist. He's Iranian. I
don't think he's Jewish. I think he's
like half Assyrian and half Armenian.
But he's a hardcore Zionist and not just
a Zionist, he is a like 1000% backer of
Reza Pahlavi to return to Iran and to
assume the Peacock Throne and blah blah
blah.
Um
and he was saying yesterday that it's
not 60%
of the Iranian people who support the
overthrow of the regime. It is 94%
and I know
There are no polls. You just make this
[__] up
to put your stooge in.
The monarchists are crazy online. I mean
I saw some they've been passing around
the message that Iran only became Muslim
100 years ago.
No, that was 1000 years ago.
>> 1000 years ago, yes. And I get that
there are still Zoroastrians and
Elliot Cowan Patrick Bet-David is
Jewish? Okay, I stand corrected. I
wasn't sure. You're not Jewish? No, I'm
not Jewish.
>> But I know he's not ethnic Persian. He's
Armenian.
Yeah, 94% of his family
Literally I've been asking online like
from these you know these Persian
monarchists See this is what I get for
listening to people in the chat.
Everybody wants the Shah back. I find
that very hard to believe considering
how brutal the Shah was and the fact
that he was overthrown by his own
people, right? I mean it wasn't like he
was cooed out by any foreign
power quite the quite to the contrary.
So he
but yeah they they literally these these
Persian monarchists they just they do
polls of like anything
Walk me through this.
>> Oh I don't owe you an apology it's not
>> tell me this I it's not I'm not I I
don't want an apology. I I enjoy talking
to you. The last time we spoke
I think out of the seven clips that we
posted, three of them was
upset Jews cuz it was comments you made
that were bad against Masada. We played
I thought it was very revealing. I
thought it was great.
But walk me through each of these.
Number one, hardcore Zionist, 100%
backer of Pahlavi and then 94%. Tell me.
Okay, the reason I said that is because
of Netanyahu's appearance, number one.
Um
and uh
and the comments that you made about
Pahlavi, like why hasn't this guy called
me back? I want him on the show. Like
why? He's irrelevant? He's a clown? Why
hasn't he called me back? I had him on
the show two times.
>> Yeah, but he when you first invited him
>> Do you know what happened there? He's
asking for help. He cuz the interviewer,
the Iranian interviewer that interviewed
me, is asking me
"Are you Are you going to help him? Are
you going to help Reza Pahlavi?" The And
we're speaking in Farsi and English.
And I said, "No." He asked me for help.
I never heard heard back from him, but I
made some very bad remarks about the
guy. Have you heard what I've said about
them?"
>> No, I'd love to.
>> I I don't know how you You must not know
how monarchists think of me right now.
No, I do You know they can't stand me
today.
Good. Do you No, no, it's not good. I
like his father. I don't think he's a
strong leader.
>> He's not. He was following me, his wife
was following me, his daughter was
following me. Everybody unfollowed. The
monarchists attacked me because I called
them Oh, it it is in shambles with me
and that relationship, right? Maybe play
clip
>> a that's a natural consequence.
>> you want to play down That's a badge of
honor. I'm going to leave Iran and go
get By the way, you know what's the
biggest thing that Iranian people are
saying? "Hey, Reza Pahlavi, why don't
you go to Azerbaijan
and and say a few words from there. Come
closer to Iran. Show some stuff." He's
not doing it. The one thing about Trump,
let me tell you what was very crystal
clear about Trump, about Milei, about
Bukele. You know what it was? They're
willing to do the leg work. They're
willing to go out there. They're willing
to pay the price. They're willing to
drive. They're willing to work their
tails off.
It's very obvious. We the markets said,
"Who is this crazy Elvis-looking guy
from Argentina? There is no way he'll
ever win making out with people on
stage." Guess what? He won. Who is this
Bukele guy that's in his early
[clears throat] mid-30s? And by the way,
let me give you what's going to be
confusing. I have a painting of his dad
at my house.
So, I'm a fan of his father.
So, this is this is not like a bash
towards
the family.
>> No, of course.
>> And so, but this is towards I was
critical of him because for 47 years
he's been talking about he wants to have
Iran be free and he didn't do it. And
And keep in mind, a part of me is, yeah,
that's the painting in my house. That's
a 15-ft painting. His father's right in
the middle. My criticism is of him. But
I was watching, you know, I'm like, why
did somebody tell you I'm a Zionist? Did
you Who's that?
>> It was in the It was in the chat.
>> No, no, but I was reading the chat.
>> Did any other influencers that you go
and do interviews with? Did anybody
whisper to you off camera, "Hey, be
careful with Patrick. He's a Zionist."
Yes. Who was that? Oh, I I don't want to
out him like that, but he said, "Oh,
you're going on PBD?" I said, "Yeah." He
said, "Be careful. Patrick comes out
swinging on Israel." Is this a big name?
Yeah, it's pretty big name. One of the
biggest names?
>> [laughter]
>> So, then I know who it is.
>> want to I don't want to out him.
>> Was his family in the CIA before, maybe?
I I I I've got to stop.
>> Okay. But But But I want to apologize on
the record because I was wrong. Okay.
So, so that and and the and the the Bibi
side because Do you know who's the only
person in the world that interviewed
Bibi and Nick Fuentes within 30 days?
>> It's got to be you.
>> It's only me. It's got to be.
>> You So, you know what the problem is
with me, John? This is the problem.
The same people that want freedom of
speech that pitch it
>> Yeah. don't practice it. Yeah.
What do I mean by that? They generally
want to only talk to people that agree
with them.
>> Yes. It's You and I don't agree on maybe
a few things.
>> No, which is why I so enjoy the
conversation. I love the conversation
because
my my thoughts are Alicia, just bring it
to me. It's totally fine. My thoughts
are it's like man, I I don't know. He
He's a CIA guy. He must know more than I
do. You know, he has some experience. I
want to know. But
>> I'm wrong and I apologize.
>> go to the other one cuz I want to clear
all of this up. Let's go to the one
about when you said 94%. I'd love to
know when I said 94%. Rob, can you take
one of the language learning models?
Matter of fact, why don't we do both of
them? Take uh take ChatGPT and do Grok
and ask a question, how do you want to
pose this question? What percentage of
Iranians don't support the IRGC?
What percentage of Iranians don't
support
the IRGC?
Okay, ask the same exact question.
So, what we'll typically do is we'll ask
different and we'll go do our own and
then we'll look at the numbers that's
being given. Okay.
Wow. This is which one? What does it
say? Around 80 to 92% of Iranians appear
to not support the IRGC based on
available polls. Support the like the
direct polling on the IRGC challenge and
due to Iran repression, surveillance,
and self-censorship. Okay, great. Leaked
internal Iranian government poll 2025
commissioned by the presidency. A
confidential report found 92% of
Iranians hate the regime.
And that's from Yahoo, explicitly
including supreme leader Khamenei and
the IRGC, not just specific officials or
policies.
This was cited by Iranian experts in
alliance with widespread
dissatisfaction.
Gamon is the one that I saw. Uh by the
way, I haven't even seen the one above
that we're reading for the
Go to the Gamon one. Gamon says what?
Independent large online poll of 10,000,
13 to 14% have confidence in the IRGC.
So, that leaves another 86.
And what does it say? Broader regime
rejection, only about 15 to 20% want
Islamic Republic to continue. 70 to 80%
favor regime change or major
transformation. High agreement, 70% with
designating the IRGC as a terrorist
organization in Iran. Can you go to the
Is this
ChatGPT or
>> was Grok.
>> Okay, let's see what ChatGPT says. Zoom
in a little bit.
Okay, so direct IRGC split 2019 Maryland
poll, 80%. Uh Maryland Iran poll, so
that's Maryland. So, you can criticize
that because that's from here, 80%.
Gamin is the same one. I think Gamin is
from Netherlands, 71% of Iranians
oppose.
20% support. So, you see what numbers
were repeated. We're repeating the
reports that are coming in. So, it's not
a You're you're right and I'm wrong and
I apologize.
No, I I appreciate that. And the And the
last one I want to show you, which is
crazy, to get this out of the way so we
can have our
uh uh
conversation, is do you know who I
brought on the podcast who never agreed
to go on the podcast with anybody? And
when he came in,
he was the most suspicious guy here
looking at me saying, "Why do you have
me on the podcast?" You know who it was?
>> No, who's that?
>> The co-founder of IRGC. No.
>> That guy right there. Mohsen Sazegara.
Okay?
Do you know who he was?
>> I missed that. So, check this out. I'm
going to I'm going to show this for you.
So, if you go a little bit lower to see
who is He's the founder of Go a little
bit lower.
Put IRGC arrest, blah blah blah blah
blah.
Can we find the IRGC there with him and
Khomeini?
Uh okay, right there in the middle.
There he is. An Iranian journalist and
political He was the founder of the
Islamic Revolutionary Guard
Corps after the Iranian Revolution. He
was the guy It was between him and
Khomeini that started the IRGC. My god.
He would do the intro to all the tapes
where they would send in for Iranians to
listen before the revolution happened to
pin
Pahlavi's people against him. This was
the voice. Then you had Khomeini. I had
him on the podcast. And the claim was
that SAVAK killed 100,000 people. Now,
keep in mind, he's the propaganda guy.
>> Sure. That said, SAVAK, which is, you
know,
uh
>> Intelligence service.
>> Pahlavi's CIA, Pahlavi's Mossad, right?
>> Right.
At the end of the podcast, I wanted to
ask him,
"It's been 40-something years now. You
were involved. Was it a lie that Shah
killed 100,000 people?"
This is not a fan of Right. This is not
a Shah a fan of the Pahlavi. He did not
come in knowing what we were going to
talk about. Look at his answer here. Go
ahead, Rob. Compare Shah with Khomeini.
Let me say my judgment now.
That many documents have come out and
you know, for instance, on those days
opposition claimed that 100,000
political prisoners Shah has.
Uh there are 100,000 political prisoners
in Iran. That was false.
It was only 3,000. 3,500.
>> 3,000
few hundred.
>> Right. Uh
This is the final round of your speech.
>> Shah with Khomeini, definitely I
I already said first of all his
personality Shah
was a better guy than Khomeini.
First, second
uh
his [clears throat]
what he did for Iran
because that he believed in
you know, modernization of Iran
was definitely better than Islamic
Republic. As I said You can pause it. I
would suggest if you want to watch it,
watch it. It's fascinating cuz it's a
little back and I'll text it to you.
I think you'll enjoy it, but
these are my positions. My concern is
John, people that have had good
relationships. There's this one guy that
I think he's the head of the snake
that behind closed doors is creating
division and creating rumors and stories
about and he's a very influential guy.
Could be the same guy that told you
stuff about me. Very heavy weight guy.
Very very heavy weight guy. I think
we're talking about the same person. If
I tell you I've heard 10 people that he
said stuff about me behind closed doors,
that's a small number.
Wow. So this keeps coming back to me.
I'm like, what is his issue? What is his
challenge? We won't talk about the name
cuz I don't want you to be in an
uncomfortable position. I'm not going to
push that topic. All I'm saying is I
wanted to make sure I presented this to
you and any pushback you have, please go
for it. I'm all ears. No, no, I owe you
an apology. I said you've you've shown
me wrong and I I'm sorry that I uh
perpetuated an untruth. And by the way,
I don't even know what a Zionist is.
What does a Zionist mean nowadays? What
is it like it's like an N-word like
people God forbid they say What would
you say Zionist is?
>> that the definition of Zionism has has
changed. Now, I think it's much more
it's much more well, depending on your
point of political
view, more reactionary or more
more radical
than it was when it originated in the UK
in the late 19th century. Now, it is
now it is
it is political Judaism strictly for
political purposes, not for religious
purposes.
at the cost of everything else.
I I had lunch yesterday with um
with um
Mother Agapea who was on the Tucker
Carlson show a couple of months back.
She's a
she's a Greek Orthodox. Actually, she's
she's Greek Orthodox, but she's in the
Russian Russian Orthodox
Archdiocese of Jerusalem.
And and we talked about this and she
said in the 25 or so years that she's
lived in Israel, that it's changed
dramatically.
And she said it's changed dramatically
because of politics. The religion hasn't
changed in thousands of years. It's the
politics that have changed and have made
it so difficult. She asked me when was
the last time I was in Israel. I said
2022 was the last time I went.
>> years ago.
>> Yeah, a few years ago. I was actually
afraid I wouldn't be able to get in, but
I didn't have any problems at all. Had a
wonderful time.
Um was appalled at some of the
the um
oh
some of the social situations I saw in
the West Bank. I've never been to Gaza.
I've never seen it with my own eyes.
Didn't have a desire to go, you know, on
my own.
And um
And it's dramatically worse just since
2022.
Dramatically worse since 2022.
>> For Palestinians, yeah. Okay. Got it.
Yeah. And you got
>> In the In the West Bank. I mean, in
Gaza, obviously, there's a war going on.
But I'm talking about in the West Bank.
Yeah. Your experience when you went
there.
I have to say, I loved every minute of
it. So your experience was a good
experience.
>> Yeah.
So you think you think the criticism cuz
it's becoming such a
nasty Like it's almost
I talked to people and some people are
like, "I don't even go on Twitter
anymore."
I actually dropped I mean, I have a guy
that runs my Twitter, but I I don't go
on Twitter anymore. Yeah, because it's
almost like each of the social media
accounts, they have their own nasty bots
that you attack and do You know, it's
part of the game. You can't have an
opinion not expect people to push back.
The moment you say, "I believe LeBron
James is the worst goat of all time."
You're going to have people that are
going to debate. The moment you have an
opinion on that, but I think I'm right.
I think he's the worst
greatest athlete of all time because he
whines so much and he [__] so much.
And go ahead and talk about it. Watch
the comment section, right?
So So we can't be like, "Oh my god,
don't call me out. It's unfair. I feel
bad." I don't think that's the problem.
We deserve to be called out. Like we
deserve to like what we just did right
now. Hey, you said it. Great. I
addressed it. I apologize. Great. We
move on and we can have our own
conversations together. I just think
it's creating division.
I just think it's creating a level of
divisiveness. So do you Do you think a
part of it is
that guys are afraid of others getting
paid? Like do Would you trust people
that are getting paid from a government
you don't trust? So let's just say some
influencers are getting paid from AIPAC
or Israel. Some influencers are getting
paid from Russia. Some influencers are
getting paid from Qatar. Some
influencers are getting paid. You think
that's what the fear is where the market
believes that people are paid
mouthpieces that you don't trust them? I
think that's probably a part of it. But
I think that the other part, and a very
powerful part is is professional
jealousy.
Yeah, I think I I I feel very strongly
that a lot of this is professional
jealousy. I I hear it about you, I hear
it about Tucker, I hear it about Sean
Ryan. People are jealous. They're
jealous of people's success.
And you know, what easier thing to do
than to just go on Twitter and start
yelling about somebody?
Yeah, there there's a there's an
influencer.
I'm not even going to say her name cuz
she doesn't deserve for her name to be
said.
Uh who just out of the clear blue sky
attacked me viciously a couple of
weekends ago. I was never important
enough to attack.
And I've never met this woman and just
came out and attacked.
And heavy weight or middle weight? Heavy
weight.
>> a heavy weight. Okay, got it.
>> And uh
I uh I'm a communist.
Nobody in my I'm decidedly capitalist
first of all. Nobody's ever in my life
called me a communist. And I actually
had to chuckle out loud when I read it
that I'm a communist, I'm a spy for the
Russians. No, I have a TV show
that uh that is produced by a company in
Miami.
And RT International happens to license
it. So they run it, other platforms run
it. All of a sudden I'm a Russian spy.
Like, "Oh, you figured that out all by
yourself, huh? Oh, he's got a TV show
that runs once a week on this Russian
network. He must be a Russian spy and a
communist." Like, news flash, have you
ever been to a history class?
There are no communists running Russia
anymore.
Not for a very long time.
But you know, she just
rolled out of bed. I say this all the
time and my friends hate when I say it
cuz it's mean-spirited, but any slob can
roll out of bed, log on to YouTube or
Twitter and criticize. That doesn't mean
we have to respond to them. Yeah, it's
going to be non-stop.
It is it is not to be That's not going
to slow down anytime soon. And And I
wonder like what words no longer carry
weight. I don't know if being called a
communist carries the weight of the
'80s. No, exactly. Exactly.
>> In the '80s that might that might have
stung a little bit.
>> Yeah. I I like bigot. Today does bigot
does bigot have the meaning today of the
'90s? I don't think so.
>> remember this this little mini trend on
on Facebook when
when COVID first started? Uh admit to
to um
uh prejudice. Mhm.
And I thought, okay, I'm going to I'm
going to do this. So, I go on Facebook.
I said, I admit I am prejudiced against
Amish people.
I am.
I grew up with the Amish. I don't like
them. They're mean, mean-spirited. They
talk about
>> [laughter]
>> They talk about
>> You posted this on Facebook?
>> Yeah, yeah. And people jumped all over
me. I'm like, people, I'm joking. It's a
joke. What's wrong with you? People need
to lighten up.
Yeah.
But this this this this is the current
situation we find ourselves in.
>> We are. We are It's a And I And I hope
what I don't know if with the
I do think we're going to get to a point
where, you know, you know how today Las
Vegas I don't know if you've been to
Vegas. I'm sure you've been there a long
period of time.
Vegas isn't what it used to be 20 years
ago. You go to Vegas, it's like it's a
freaking ghost town. Like it used to be
packed. Yes, it did.
>> and then you see the stats where they're
saying, why is Vegas having a hard time
today? And And you'll see numbers where
they're saying Vegas having a hard time
because they're no longer Kids are no
longer drinking alcohol like they used
to.
Uh going and hooking up today, I don't
need to go to Vegas. There's Tinder. So,
everything Vegas offers,
I now have access locally, and I'm no
longer interested in drinking alcohol
like a lot of you know, maybe I did back
in the days.
And so, to me, I think we're going to
come to a point where people are going
to go on social media diets. I really
believe that. I think I think people
going to go on phone diets. I think
people going to be like, "Dude, I am
setting this guy aside. I'll come in to
get my information that I need, but I'm
not going through it the way I was
addicted. Just What did they call it? Is
it death scrolling or doom scrolling?
>> scrolling. Doom scrolling. Just kind of
going through it, man. That can really
The probably has some effects on people
today.
>> I think it probably does. You know what?
I I'll admit another thing.
I doom scroll at night. But, you know,
funny thing,
the algorithm is relatively quick about
determining what interests you.
I have
never
seen one of my own shorts.
Never. Not one.
What I watch all freaking night long as
I'm laying in bed
>> [laughter]
>> is people filming in public. Yeah. Like
taking pictures of people's license
plates, and then the people who are in
the cars lose their minds and get out,
and then they have to get pepper
sprayed, and then the cops come.
I love that stuff. Yeah.
>> Because it's all about the First
Amendment, right? But, I've never seen
my own shorts. Well, I've seen a lot of
your shorts. You know, one thing one
thing I do is I I watch this this
Jamaican pastor. I've probably seen him
preach couple hundred times. Uh Rob,
have you seen that clip or no?
>> No. Well, you know, I don't know if I'm
going to find it or not. This guy just
This This guy fires me up. He's so
funny. But, anyways, it just tells you
the the the appetite and what things
we're interested in. Okay, so let's
let's go into issues.
Um Iran
uh uh war US. I think you were the first
one
that said 3 days before the attack that
it was going to happen. I think you said
it on the 19th. Was it March 19th? And
and Marcus is like, "What's he talking
Do you have that clip?" I took a lot of
[__] for that, too. Well, you did, but
you ended up being right when you
announced it. You said, "Hey, here's
what I think is going on. Ex-CIA agent
reveals US could attack Iran as early as
Monday."
And you said that on the 19th, 20th. I
don't know the exact dates.
And Rob, if you have the video, I
wouldn't mind showing it because to to
give him credit that he was the first
guy that announced it and it happened.
And so how did you know? What where did
the information come from? The truth is
I've got a friend at the White House. I
have friends at the Pentagon, friends at
the CIA, friends at the FBI.
And And this was the criticism, too,
Patrick. A A guy A guy posted a comment
like, "Oh, we're supposed to believe
that that people just walk out of the
White House and walk up to this criminal
and tell him classified defense
secrets?" And I'm like, "Yeah."
That's exactly what you should believe
because that's what happened.
So I've got friends all over Washington.
I've been in Washington for 44 years,
right? We're all neighbors and we hang
out together. I'm the only person in my
church who's not a retired colonel or
lieutenant colonel in the military,
seriously. It's like a VFW meeting at
church every Sunday. [laughter]
And uh
And so yeah, a friend of mine said,
"Hey, listen, there's some [__] going on
at the White House." I said, "Yeah, what
are you hearing?" He said, "We really
are going to attack Iran."
Is Is this a CIA guy or no? Is this a
>> He's He's a
Uh I should probably protect his
>> Just if it's military or intelligence.
>> Military.
>> Military, okay.
And he said we're probably going to be
attacking on Monday.
>> And I said, "Well, wait a minute. Wait a
minute." I said, "I've been really
hedging my my language here and what
I've been saying," this is what I told
him, "what I've been saying is one of
the very first lessons that I learned at
the CIA is that if you want to determine
American military intentions, watch
naval movements."
You know, we can fly troops out all over
the place, it doesn't make any
difference. If you're going to send an
an entire aircraft carrier strike group,
you mean business. If you're going to
send two of them, you're going to war.
And we sent two. Mhm.
And that was the determination I made.
>> Interesting. So that was given to you
you and Is this it, Rob?
>> Yes, sir. Go forward. Uh I have a friend
uh former CIA officer
who was at the White House this morning
talking to his friends
and he says that a decision has been
made
to attack Iran on Monday or Tuesday. The
president yesterday gave the Iranians 10
days to uh
to you know, accept our proposals for an
end to their ballistic missile program,
an end to
to uh their uranium enrichment program
and It's pretty wild. So, you So, let me
ask you when when normally cuz you're in
a community and people talk. Like like
I'm in the financial industry. I I was
no longer
So, my company almost four years ago.
You still have friends? For sure. So, it
when that happens, cuz there's two
different ways of leaking information.
The one information is leaking where
it's like
talk about it. Drop it. One information
is John, please don't say this to
anybody else. Right. Which one was this?
I think this was please don't say this
to anybody else to him.
To him. Because this was real military
planning.
He panicked and said something to me.
But you're exactly right. There are two
different kinds of leaks. First of all,
the White House and the Pentagon leak
like a sieve. But usually those leaks
are authorized leaks. Let's get an idea
what public opinion's going to be.
>> That's right. Let's just see what the
networks say if we do X.
That's not what this
>> That's been happening for decades. This
is just don't tell anybody and you ended
up you ended up sharing it and then
ended up being right. So, the guy And
this isn't
>> Joe Kent that you were talking
>> Oh, no, no. No, You and Joe don't have a
You and Joe don't have a relationship.
>> No. That would be an interesting podcast
of the two of you guys talking
>> enjoy that very much.
>> Because
>> You know what what I did? As soon as he
went public, I I called a producer that
I know and I said, "Any chance you have
Joe Kent's contact information because
I'm a member of this group called
Veteran Intelligence Professionals for
Sanity, VIPs. And we wanted to give him
our It's called the Sam Adams Award for
Integrity and Intelligence." And so, she
sent me his uh his info and we gave him
the award. Beautiful.
>> But I've never spoken to the man. So
what do you what do you think where we
are now? So if if you if that was then
that this has happened, is there any
talks today of this coming to an end?
Because there was supposed to be a
ceasefire. All right, let's do
ceasefire.
Ah, I don't know if both sides committed
to the full ceasefire, but let's just
say it was a cease-ish fire that they
did. Yesterday, yesterday at 4:45 in the
morning our time, Iran attacks three
ships. They seized two of them. One is
from Panama. I think one of them's from
Greek Greece if I'm not mistaken. Yeah.
It is. So they take that. And so they
and then President Trump is like the
ceasefire is continuing indefinitely.
What does that really mean? The
negotiations are going back and forth.
Where do you think we are today?
I think the situation is unique because
Donald Trump is president.
Donald Trump has this
innate ability
to spin things better than any previous
president, I believe. I could actually
see Donald Trump saying
in a nationally televised announcement,
"We won. It's all over. We're coming
home."
I could see that happening. I'm not
saying it's going to happen tomorrow,
but I could see it ending that way. Now,
with that said,
I think that
this is one of those times where we need
to let the diplomats do what they're
trained to do.
We have not made great use of the
Omanis. We've not made great use of the
Qataris or the Algerians. I mean, these
are all countries that we work with,
work through
over the course of decades to carry out
diplomatic communications with Iran.
I think the bottom line is
we have one idea of what we want from
Iran, but the Israelis have a different
idea.
You notice, for example, uh
the president announces a ceasefire in
Lebanon and boom, 24 hours later the
Israelis bomb.
It's because we have competing
interests. You know, there's this old
saying in Washington, there's no such
thing as permanent friends, just
permanent interests. Well, our interests
diverge with those of the Israelis on on
some of these issues, specifically Iran
and Lebanon. So, I think really Patrick,
the bottom line is at the end of this,
we're going to end up with something
that looks very much like the JCPOA.
And we're just going to say, "Oh, we
won. It's all over. We have this
agreement. Peace is at hand."
I think the real sticking point is going
to be
what to do with the uranium that's
already been enriched, even if it's only
60% or 80% or whatever it is it happens
to be.
Um the American position is that they
have to give it to us.
The old position was they could transfer
it to China, the United Arab Emirates,
Saudi Arabia. We've changed our position
on that. It has to come to us. They
won't send it to us. That's going to be
a sticking point. But otherwise, you
know what? I think that I think that
this conflict has also um
brought to light some American
weaknesses.
And I think the most important one is
that the conflict has pushed the
Iranians deeper into the embrace of
China, Russia, and India.
All three of them all four of them are
BRICS countries. We also know that there
are
rumblings of a unified uh BRICS
currency. It's probably 30 years down
the road, but it's going to happen one
of these days. I think this conflict is
going to make it happen a little bit
more quickly. And that's going to
further weaken the United States.
So, if if
for example, the international community
either drops the petrodollar or begins
trading buying oil in yuan, we're
screwed. It's going to have a long-term
deleterious effect on the American
economy.
And I think that this conflict pushed
things in that direction.
Yeah, and behind closed doors, China
apparently got caught sending a ship.
>> Yeah. Where the president said they send
them a gift. What's in the gift? Well,
it's secret. I can't tell you what's in
the gift, but it was what? Chemical,
missile, uh uh uh
weapons, you know, kind of helping them
out to have some missiles to defend
themselves.
>> That's right. So, you know, we've always
known they've been close cuz when when
uh
China signed that 25-year deal with uh
Iran, I don't know what the number was,
400 billion dollars, 300 billion
dollars, it was a big number. We've
always seen them being close and Iran
being close to Russia cuz Iran would
sell Sure.
>> their uh is it Shahed uh
uh drones? The drones that they make.
>> They pump those drones out like nobody's
business.
>> So, kind of reminds you what happened
with Ukraine and Russia, where Ukraine
was attacked with their small drones,
and they're the best producers of
drones.
So, you see similarities there. But, the
difference is Ukraine was protected by
NATO.
>> Right. Right? So, and us, cuz it was
under Biden, so they got so much money
and funding. So,
Russia had to kind of sit there and say,
"What are we going to do here?" That's
why everybody's so shocked
at revelations that the Russians and the
Chinese are giving the Iranians
targeting information. Of course,
they're giving them targeting
information.
>> We give the Ukrainians targeting
information. This is We The Russians did
this to us in Vietnam. Yeah, but the
difference is, what you said is very
important.
You said the difference is uh uh the
Trump effect, right? He knows how to
negotiate. If there's anything we've
learned from 2016 to 2026,
uh in choosing presidents,
if you ask somebody a question in 2000,
"What qualities do you want in a
president?" Top five, they would say,
"Diplomacy, you know, uh being
presidential, you know, great orator." I
don't know what else you put in there,
right? You would probably put a few
different things. You know, good
understanding of foreign affairs and all
this stuff. You know what people are
realizing from '16 to today? Negotiation
skills. Yeah.
>> And the guy's a The guy's a phenomenal
negotiator. Obama wasn't a negotiator,
you know?
>> O- Biden wasn't a negotiator, Biden.
>> Biden knew he was president.
>> You're right. I mean, that was like a,
you know, very funny situation. So,
there's a So, So, the part becomes
Trump uses the pulpit to speak to his
allies and enemies.
You know, I thought G and I were
friends. He said, "But it's okay. Maybe
that's what happens. We'll see what will
take place. I hope he's not doing it.
But if he is, I'll have a conversation
with them. Who knows what we'll do?"
I I have to add, too,
that Democrats have consistently
underestimated him.
They treat him like he's an idiot, like
he's some kind of a buffoon, and he's
not. He knows exactly what he's doing.
>> Do you still support him? Do you think
he is You know, I I
>> If we If no camera's on, we're at a
place, no one's famous, people you
trust,
would you say you're happy he's your
president today instead of anybody else?
>> Uh yeah, I would say that. I would say
that. Um
I I have very strong feelings about the
Democrats. They're strongly negative.
Is what they are.
Um I believe that behind the smiling
faces and the advanced, you know,
college degrees, it's just a cabal of
criminals coming out of that Obama
administration and extending into the
Biden administration.
Yes, the Trump administration has had
problems, too. But
for example, when Kash Patel was was
named FBI director,
I celebrated
because the FBI's broken and it needed
to be torn down to its studs. Same with
the CIA. Now, that hasn't necessarily
happened, but at least the idea was
there, the thought was there. And
instead, it's the Democrats that have
become the party of the status quo. It's
the Democrats that have become the party
of the of the deep state.
And we need to shake things up. I've
been in Washington for 44 years,
Patrick. I moved to Washington the week
after I turned 18 years old to go to
college. And back then,
you know, Democrats and Republicans used
to live in these group houses up on
Capitol Hill. They'd play poker on
Fridays. They'd go to church together on
Sundays. Everybody was friends. 44 is
what? What year is 1982. Wow. So, this
is pre-Reagan. This is Wow.
>> when Reagan was first elected. He'd been
president for a year when I moved to
Washington.
>> What a time to move to DC.
>> I'll say. What a time to move to DC.
>> god. And I'll tell you a funny story.
Don't think less of me.
It was really cold one night, and I
wanted to go for a walk.
And nobody would go for a walk with me.
I lived I was going to GW University,
George Washington University,
two blocks, three blocks from the White
House. It was December, it was cold.
Nobody wanted to go for a walk. So, my
girlfriend said, "Okay, I'll go for a
walk with you." So, we walk around the
White House when you could walk around
the White House. Now, it's impossible.
But we noticed that the Let me think.
That the West Gate was open. And I said,
"Oh, something's going to happen. Let's
stand here for a second."
And sure enough,
Reagan pulls out in the presidential
limousine. He's going As it turned out,
he was going to the Kennedy Center for
the Kennedy Center Honors.
I thought that I hated Reagan at the
time. I was 18 years old. But it's the
president of the United States. So, I
started to applaud. Even though you hate
him,
cuz you're a liberal at the He's the
president. I was liberal at the time.
He's the president. I started applauding
him. They stopped the limousine, and he
rolls the window down.
>> Stop it. Mhm. I get chills. Look at
this. Stop.
>> chills thinking about it.
And my girlfriend's like, "Oh my god."
And so, we said, "Keep
>> [laughter]
>> I go, "Keep up the good work, Mr.
President."
Even though you're not for him.
>> [laughter]
>> And your girlfriend, I'm assuming, is
also not
>> Afterwards, she's like, "You know, you
can't tell anybody that this just
happened, right?"
I said, "I can't believe he stopped the
car."
>> Did he step out or did he pull down the
window?
>> It was freezing cold. He just rolled
down the window and he said, "Thanks for
your support." Like that. Wow.
>> And then years years later, my brother's
visiting me from LA and we're walking
down Constitution Avenue. There used to
be like a little tiny Barnes & Noble in
the National Press Club at What is that?
14th and
Pennsylvania Avenue. So, we're walking
down the street and we notice two limos
parked there. And my brother said, "Oh,
I wonder who this is." I said, "It's
probably cabinet member. You see them
around town all the time."
Um and he says, "Well, let's wait. Let's
wait. I want to see who it is." I'm
like, "Okay."
So, we're standing there and then out of
the Barnes & Noble comes Bill Clinton
with Chelsea. It's a Sunday morning.
They just went in to buy some books.
>> [laughter]
>> And I didn't know what to say. So, I
just shout, "Keep abortion safe and
legal, Bill."
>> that.
>> [laughter]
>> You didn't say that. And he goes, "I'm
trying." And he comes over and shakes
hands.
He, by the way, he is the smoothest out
of all of them.
>> Oh, I've got some Clinton stories, man.
Do you? Like face-to-face like
Face-to-face from my CIA days.
>> What happened? Oh my god, I was assigned
to the American Embassy in Athens,
Greece
from 1998 to 2000. This is immediately
after the Monica Lewinsky scandal.
Woolsey is Was Woolsey the CIA director
CIA?
>> Woolsey had left
>> Cuz he was only there for 2 years.
>> Yeah, he left in '94.
>> Okay, so that's after.
>> Right. Got it. And was replaced by John
Deutch, who was horrible. So,
we get this notification from the White
House, the president's going to come to
Greece.
We ask The ambassador asked him, it was
Nick Burns at the time, "Please don't
come on the 17th of November because 17
November is the name of the big
terrorist group that's active in Greece
because that's the day that the that the
military attacked the Athens Polytechnic
University killed dozens of students. He
comes right on the 17th of November.
It's like the worst possible day of the
year. But anyway,
the ambassador had us pull jobs out of a
hat. Like literally he had a hat and
with jobs written on scraps of paper. I
was the luckiest guy. Hit the lottery
that day. I pulled out My job was to be
the note taker in the president's
meeting with the prime minister.
So, the meeting is at the
Intercontinental Hotel in the
presidential suite, almost the entire
top floor of the hotel. And it's it's
Clinton, Secretary of State Albright,
National Security Advisor Berger, the
ambassador, and me.
And for the Greeks it was the prime
minister, the defense minister, the
foreign minister, and the Greek note
taker.
So, we go there. There was a table
almost the whole length of the room just
covered in food and
coffee and tea and drinks and anything
your heart desired was there. So,
everybody comes in and they sit down.
I'm standing against one wall with my
notebook. The Greek note taker is
standing against the opposite wall with
his notebook. And the president says to
the prime minister, "Can I offer you a
cup of coffee, a tea, something to eat?"
No, and this one says
>> President offered a prime minister.
>> Yeah. And then he turns to me and he
says,
"May I offer you something to eat?"
I said, "Oh, no thank you, Mr.
President. I'm I'm good." And he goes,
"Are are you with me?" And I said,
>> got it.
>> I said, "Yes, sir, I'm with you." And he
said, "I thought you were Greek." And I
said, "I I kind of am, but I'm not, but
I'm with you." So,
I'm ready to take notes in this
incredibly important meeting
and it's
"We love you. You love us. We have lots
and lots of Greeks in America. They own
all the diners. They're all successful.
You're the birthplace of democracy and
mathematics and medicine and we love
you. And then the Greeks are like, we
love you, too.
When our economy couldn't handle all
these Greeks in the '20s and '30s, they
went to America and you gave them a
chance and we love you. And I'm like
waiting for something important to write
down. There's nothing.
So, at the end of it everybody stands
up, they all shake hands, Clinton hugs
everybody and they leave. Then,
Clinton walks out with Albright.
I'm sorry. Yeah, that's right. And then
Berger walks out with the ambassador.
So, I walk out after them. I'm standing
about 2 ft away from Clinton and
Albright. They finish their
conversation. Albright goes to the other
two. So, I'm just standing there 2 ft
away from Clinton and just as she walks
away, the elevator at the end of the
hall opens up and Hillary walks off with
Chelsea.
The story's about to change. She has
this puss on her face like this.
She walks right up to us.
And one thing about Clinton, I I noticed
it from the very moment that I met him,
he hates silence.
He wants to be joshing and joking and
laughing and telling stories and
and she's just standing there looking at
him.
And so, he says,
"We sure had a good time at the
Parthenon this morning, didn't we,
Hill?"
She's just staring at him. So, he
repeats himself. "We sure had a good
time at the Parthenon this morning,
didn't we, Hill?" And she says, "Jesus
Christ, Bill, it's raining all day. I'll
be in the room." And she walks between
us. And I'm looking at him like, "You
poor man. You have to sleep next to that
every night." He looks right at me and
he goes,
"Let's get out of here."
So, the two of us walk to the elevator,
the Secret Service runs after us and
then everybody else files in. We go down
to the basement. There are 500 screaming
women from the Greek
Greek-American
Business Women's Association. And he
gave this raucous,
you know, vintage Bill Clinton. It was
that Clinton magic that people used to
talk about. I saw it with my own eyes.
Yeah, it's it's funny that I can't tell
you how many stories of people you ask
of of Clinton, Bill, how many of them is
positive? Yeah. Of how he was. And how
it is with Hillary. We were at a Oh, she
was just
awful.
>> Is that the only experience with
Hillary?
>> No, no, no. I I
encountered her a number of times. After
I left the agency, I was the chief
investigator on the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee. And um she had just
left the committee to become Secretary
of State. So she used to come back all
the time. And she was impossible.
Impossible. I mean, they all are at that
at that level. John Kerry was the one
who See, now you got me on a roll. I'm
going to be criticizing everybody. But
uh John Kerry hired me
just just as he became the chairman in
January of 2009, he called me and said,
"I'm going to reconstitute the
investigative function at the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee. Would you
like to be the investigator?" And I
said, "I'd love to be the investigator."
So he said, "I want to make an impact.
We want to, you know, root out
wrongdoing." I said, "Great."
Nothing could have been further from the
truth.
And I'll I'll tell you why if you don't
mind me rambling on for a moment.
Uh before I went up to the hill,
I struck up something of a of a
a proper friendship with Mack McLarty,
who had been Clinton's chief of staff.
Mack had partnered with Henry Kissinger
to make Kissinger McLarty Associates.
That became McLarty Associates. And Mack
gave me an office in his suite of
offices. It was a very generous thing to
do.
So Bill Richardson, the former governor
of New Mexico, congressman, Secretary of
Energy, Ambassador to the United
Nations, he was also at McLarty
Associates and Bill and I totally hit it
off. I loved this guy. I even voted for
him for president after he dropped out
of the race.
>> Stop it.
>> I did. He's just a wonderful guy. He's
He passed away now, but he's a
wonderful, wonderful man.
So,
he came up to me one day and he said,
"Hey, listen, can you keep a secret?" I
said, "Of course."
And he said, uh, "I invited, uh, I
invited Obama to my house to watch the,
uh, Super Bowl. This was in 2000 January
of 2008
before the primaries."
He said, "At halftime we went for a
walk."
And he had like a thousand acres of
wasteland out in New Mexico. So, he, uh,
he says, "Obama." He put his arm around
my shoulder and he said, "Bill,
if you endorse me
and you bring the Hispanics,
Secretary of State."
And I said, "Oh my god, that's
fantastic. It's what Richardson always
wanted." He said, "I want you to be my
deputy chief of staff." I said, "Done. I
want to be ambassador to Greece in the
second term." And he says, "Yeah." He
says, "Great. Everybody's going to have
a good time. We're going to We're going
to make an impact." I said, "Great." I
run home. I tell my wife, "Oh my god,
I'm going to be the deputy chief of
staff at State."
So, fast forward a year
and Obama wins the election.
And I'm in the shower one day. I got the
radio going to listen to the news and
they said, "Former Secretary of Energy
Bill Richardson was named by
President-elect Obama today as the
Secretary of Commerce."
Not State. Uh-uh.
So, I I go into the office
and I go I go, "Mr. Secretary,
congratulations." And he comes up to me.
He goes, "What the [__] do I know about
commerce?"
>> [laughter]
>> And I said I said, "No, no, no, no.
You're looking at this wrong. We can
make this into something. There's the
Foreign Commercial Service. There's the
International Trade Representative.
Tough it out for 4 years. You become
Secretary of State in the second term.
This is good. We can We can make this
work.
Week later he quits.
Just drops out. Okay, so fast forward.
What do you mean he drops out?
>> Yeah, he dropped out. He was never
Secretary of
>> Withdrew a month later as he was being
investigated for possible improper
business dealings.
>> Yeah, they never indicted him. There
were all There was always this rumor
that he had done something improper and
nobody ever could vocalize it. So,
I I go to Capitol Hill. I become the
chief investigator in the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee and um
one thing about John Kerry Kerry always
thought always that he was smarter than
everybody else. And so, his
speechwriters would write these speeches
and he would always go off script and
just start winging it. And he always
made himself look foolish. So, I go with
him to the speech at the uh Brookings
Institution and he's giving the speech
he's reading the speech and then he goes
off topic and he says, "You know,
I was supposed to be the Secretary of
State.
I invited Obama over to my house at
Christmas."
>> Stop it. Uh-huh. And he says,
"We went for a walk after dinner." Kerry
saying this?
>> Uh-huh.
And he says, "Obama put his arm around
my shoulder and he said, John, if you
endorse me and if you do it before the
Kennedys do it,
Secretary of State."
And he says, "I got screwed out of it. I
was supposed to be Secretary of State."
So, I'm in the front row and I'm going
like this.
To him? Yeah, like discreetly. Like
you're off topic and this is not an
issue you should be talking about in
public. So, afterwards he says, "I I
know I shouldn't have said that story. I
know I And I said, "Bill Richardson has
exactly the same story." I said, "Barack
Obama promised half a dozen people that
they would be Secretary of State.
That's the kind of person he is.
He duped all of you guys."
Wow. So, it's not like he was telling
Bill's stories that Obama told us to a
bunch of people
>> Mhm. and didn't keep the promise. Nope.
He lied to everybody.
Mhm. Unfreaking believable.
Now, you wonder how much of that is a
pattern that happens often. I wonder. Or
if it was specific that if he's some
kind of sociopath. But I'll tell you
the reason why I started telling you the
story is as the investigator, he
wouldn't let me investigate anything
because he didn't want to piss off
Obama. He so desperately wanted to be
Secretary of State. So I'm doing like
the Dasht-e Leili massacre in northern
Afghanistan. I go to Afghanistan, I go
to Dasht-e Leili, they're like bones
sticking out of the ground, still have
the clothing on them. I come back, I'm
like we have to investigate this. He's
like, you're going to kill that
investigation. I said, "Senator, you're
the one who told me to go on the
investigation."
Well, you know, it's it happened a long
time ago and all these years have passed
and it's time to look forward. And it's
like, "Okay. All right." And then
somebody emails me and says, "Hey, you
know, in the new American passports,
they have these smart chips in them." I
said, "Yeah." "The chips are made in
China." I said, "Seriously?" "Yeah, you
you you have to investigate it." So I
investigate it. I go to State, I go to
the manufacturer. All the chips are made
in China and the passports are assembled
in Thailand. They're not even assembled
in the United States, American
passports. So I write up a memo and I
said, "Look, this this is potentially a
problem. I'm not saying the Chinese have
hacked into our passports. I'm saying
that this could be a problem. Maybe just
maybe we should we should manufacture
our own passports in the United States."
He's like, "Don't release that
investigation."
I said, "Why not?" "Well, we don't want
to embarrass the uh embarrass the White
House." I'm like, "Are you going to let
me do anything?" I ended up resigning
after 2 years.
He wouldn't let me do anything cuz
[clears throat] he wanted to be
Secretary of State.
Yeah, I mean he almost became a
president uh until he did the
flip-flopping thing. What was it that he
went to one place, I don't know when it
was, but it was the flip-flopping where
he's like, "It's over for this guy." He
gave two different messages. He did.
>> Was he going against Bush or he was
going against Bush, right?
>> Bush in '04 and the only reason he
didn't become president was Ohio. That
was it was that close.
>> Didn't they go to Yale together? What
they They went to Yale. So what a what
an interesting match up for both of them
to be part of the Skull and Bones and
>> Yeah, at the same time. And funny
enough, because Kerry was supposed to be
such an intellectual,
Bush's grades were better than Kerry's.
>> Bush's grades were better than Kerry. It
was like an inside joke for us. Let me
tell you one other John Kerry thing.
The first time I met him, he he called
me and invited me to come up to the
office for a conversation.
So I said, "Oh, I'd love I'd love to
come up and have a conversation." He was
in the Russell Building, which is
the historic Senate office building, the
oldest one. It's where all the big
hearings have been held through history.
So I go up there, and you go into his
private office with these, you know,
15-ft ceilings, and literally from the
floor to the ceiling, covering an entire
wall, and it's about the size of your
wall here, there were framed pictures of
him with every leader in the world, from
Gorbachev to the Dalai Lama,
everybody that matters. But when you
first walk in, right here on the side,
there was a credenza. It had three
things on it that struck me immediately.
One was a picture of him in an embrace
with
John Lennon. And they're like goofing.
Very cool. Who wouldn't want a picture
of himself with John Lennon like that?
Then on the other side, it was a picture
of him with uh Peter, Paul, and Mary,
the folk uh singers.
And uh
and uh I knew that they were close, and
he gave the eulogy at Mary Travers'
funeral.
And then in the middle
was a shadow box. And in the shadow box,
it had his Silver Star, his Bronze
Stars, and his Purple Heart.
But he famously threw those medals over
the White House fence to protest the
Vietnam War.
So I'm looking at that like, "What?"
Like everybody knows, everybody in
America knows he threw those medals over
the White House fence.
So,
we did the meeting, he offered me the
job, and I accepted it.
And uh
the chief of staff says, "Well, how did
it go?" I said it went really well. He
offered me the job, and I said yes, but
I got a question. I said,
"The shadow box with the medals." I
said, "What's up with that? Everybody
knows he threw those medals away."
And he goes, "Are you kidding?" He said,
"Those medals are the most important
things in his life." He went to the PX
that morning, and he bought copies. Wow.
>> And he threw the copies over the White
House Wow.
>> "Nobody in America knows that." Wow.
Has that story been told? Mhm. Wow.
[clears throat]
So, that was a whole, you know,
spectacle to just get
>> Wow.
>> put him on the map. He ran for
lieutenant governor of uh he he ran for
Congress and lost, ran for lieutenant
governor and won, then ran for Congress
and won, and then when Paul Songas
retired, uh he became a senator.
Well, you look, you you know, he'll go
down as one of the biggest heavyweights.
He's a heavyweight
>> a heavyweight on the on the on the Oh,
yeah. you know, Democratic side. And the
Bill guy that you were talking about, I
think the Bill guy was
I don't know what happened with him, but
there was some recent files that came up
with him and uh Epstein, if I'm not
mistaken.
>> Yes. Oh, it broke my heart. Nine times
he reached out to Epstein and whatever,
even after he was uh convicted, and even
visited the island. I don't know if he
including a visit to Epstein's island to
Heartbreaking. Richardson's schedule
means with Epstein as late as 2018,
according to emails including a batch of
more than 3 million documents released.
Yeah, so
>> Yeah. Hi, everybody. I'm John Kiriakou,
former CIA officer. Please find me on
Mett. We have a lot to talk about. CIA,
FBI, DOD, torture, secret prisons,
international renditions. Maybe you or
your child want to apply for a job at
the CIA and are looking for some tips.
Let me know. There's a lot we can talk
about. You pick the subject, we'll make
it happen. Again, it's on Manet. Thanks
and I'll see you soon. How do you handle
some of this stuff yourself? Cuz you you
you spent a lot of time with these guys.
>> Oh, yeah. I spent a lot of time with
these guys.
You know, when I was a kid
well, a kid. When I was in college, I
used to buy this this book every 2 years
called the Almanac of American Politics
written by Michael Barone and Brant
Fujimori. It's it's the Bible of
American politics. The uh the Almanac of
American
There it is. And
I was just so
thrilled to be in Washington, going to
school in Washington. Every Friday, I
never had Friday classes. So, every
Friday I'd take my Almanac of American
Politics, I'd go to Capitol Hill, and
I'd get autographs
from congressmen and senators.
>> At what age? 18.
And
I was working for my congressman,
Congressman Joe Kolter. He was a
conservative Democrat from Western
Pennsylvania, pro-life, pro-gun,
pro-labor.
The old-school kind of Democrat.
>> Got it.
And um
he came into the office one day.
The
the the woman I was sitting next to, she
was engaged to a lobbyist. He happened
to be standing there. And the
congressman came in the office one day
and he goes, "I got laid last night."
And because I was an innocent kid, I
turned to the woman and I said, "He's
lying.
Mrs. Kolter's in Pittsburgh right now."
And I was like, "Oh, [__]
>> [laughter]
>> And then the lobbyist said to me,
"Buddy,
you got to stop idolizing these guys.
They're all scumbags and they all put
their pants on one leg at a time."
>> Wow. And that was the first time that I
ever started putting
these people on Capitol Hill into
perspective. Who who was the one that at
least maintained some uh that's easy.
Character and values and principles.
>> That was John McCain.
John McCain became a hero for me.
John McCain
>> Of all people, really? Of all people. I
know I know people people kind of look
at me oddly every time I say this, but
just as an example,
6 weeks before I got out of prison, I
was I was allowed to call my wife every
other day for 15 minutes. So, 6 weeks
before I got out of prison, I called her
and I said, "How's your day?" She said,
"It's great."
And I said, "Really? Why great? What
made it so great?" And she said, "The
Senate torture report was released today
and it proved that everything you said
was true." And she said, "John McCain
got up on the floor of the Senate and he
named you by name and he said that if it
wasn't for you, the American people
would have never had any idea
what the CIA was doing in their name."
This is the waterboarding The
waterboarding, yeah.
>> You became the whistleblower and I think
Obama Obama is the one that came after
you, right? He prosecuted six of you
guys. He He is eight I was the six more
than all the presidents combined.
>> Three times all previous presidents
combined. Three times in American
history.
On freaking the Espionage Act was it the
Espionage Act?
>> Act.
So, you were the sixth out of the eight.
>> the sixth out of the eight.
The Espionage Act was written in 1917
to combat German saboteurs during the
First World War.
Between 1917 and 2009, three people were
prosecuted for speaking to the press.
Just under Obama, eight of us were
Eight of us.
I remember a friend of mine at the White
House saying,
"Be careful of this guy. Obama has what
his words Obama has a Nixonian obsession
with national security leaks." And I
said, "Why?" He said, "Because John
Brennan's whispering in his ear every
single day. Prosecute. Prosecute.
Prosecute." So, he did.
Eight times. So, you going through it
with your wife 15 minutes. Hey, you
won't believe McCain had your back.
McCain
>> Yeah. you know, got up on and named you.
And when I got out of prison, well, you
know what? Before when I was working for
Kerry, Kerry's office was directly next
door to McCain's in in the Russell
building. And every time Kerry and I
would be walking out of the out of the
office like for a vote, McCain would be
walking out of his office and he would
always go out of his way to come and
shake my hand. How are you, John? I'd
say, "Doing well, Senator. How are you
doing?"
And we would always shake hands. And
then Kerry one time said, "Why don't you
and McCain get a room or something?" And
I said, "No, no, he's he's serious. He's
a sincere guy." They had this weird
love-hate relationship between They
respected each other,
but they didn't like each other.
And I said, "No, McCain's a
a sweetheart. He really is."
When I got out of prison,
this is this is the especially painful
part. I got out of prison. I was out
four or five days and I get a call from
a guy on McCain's staff.
A very serious guy. And he says,
"Senator McCain says, 'Welcome home
and he wants to know how he can be
helpful to you.'"
And I said, "Oh my god, tell him thank
you so much. He can be helpful by giving
me my pension back." I said, "These
Obama people confiscated my pension, 20
years of proud government service."
>> This is a $780,000
Correct.
>> Yep. So,
my attorney,
who's also one of my best friends,
was the Deputy Attorney General under
Reagan. And he said, "I have an idea."
We went up to meet with McCain's people.
He wrote an amendment and it was
hilarious. It was like one sentence. And
it said,
"Every American
who had his pension confiscated
for violating the Intelligence
Identities Protection Act
between October 1st and October 31st,
2012,
shall hereby have that pension
reinstated."
I'm the only person in the world.
So, McCain says,
"I'm going to slip this into the
National Defense Authorization Act." He
said, "That thing's like 3,000 pages
long. Nobody reads them." He said, "I'm
going to put it down in the bottom.
Nobody's going to pay any attention.
We're going to get you your pension
back."
So, he said, I said, "Well, but it's
going to be in the Senate version. It's
not going to be in the House version."
He said, "I'll get myself appointed to
the conference committee and I'll ensure
that it is in there in the final bill."
And then he got brain cancer.
And so, he couldn't be on the conference
committee. He was too sick. And so, they
pulled it out. And Three pages, all the
way in the back, and they pulled it out.
The 780. And they pulled it out. So,
here I am.
>> McCain is number one on the list.
>> Yeah. Go go with the stuff that we're
talking about the Espionage Act.
>> Yeah. And the stuff that Obama did. Go
go to FISA because FISA
>> Oh, yeah.
>> goes back to what? FISA starts off with
Teddy Ki- Ted Kennedy, if I'm not
mistaken. Yeah. And he pitches it and he
proposes it and I think Carter comes in.
And the concern at the time, this is
right after Watergate, if I'm not
mistaken. So, hey, this is the way for
us to catch terrorists.
And then Obama ends up using that to go
after people like you and also going
after people like Trump. Look look at
Carter Page, the poor guy.
>> Exactly.
>> They ruined his life.
>> Yeah.
You know, you make a very important
point here that there's repeating.
FISA is not new.
FISA has been around since the Carter
administration.
Um Ted Kennedy was instrumental in the
passage of FISA. Um
They believed back then that there was a
real danger of, you know, foreign
involvement in American political
machinations.
And so, they passed FISA that would
allow this secret court that sits on the
top floor of the Justice Department.
It's off-limits to everybody. The judges
are constantly rotating in and out.
They're They're sitting federal district
court judges from around the country.
And um the CIA and the FBI can go there
and say we need a secret warrant to tap
the phones of, you know, X, Y, and Z
people.
And they get it. And there's nothing in
writing
nothing that can ever be released to the
American people. So, you don't have any
idea if maybe there's a FISA warrant on
you. There's not supposed to be because
you're an American citizen, but so was
Carter Page. These are supposed to be
warrants on foreign nationals in touch
with Americans.
Well, you know, when the FISA court
turns down something like whatever it
is, 19/100 of 1% or whatever,
where's the oversight?
Who
exists in government to say, "Wait a
minute, this is wrong. You're abusing
this program."
To make it worse, Section 702 is being
debated right now.
Section 702 is something that has to
come up for re-authori- re-authorization
every 2 years.
And
what Section 702 does
is it allows these continued secret Here
it is.
Secret warrantless
uh wiretaps
on people. But again,
you know, on whom? And what's the
threshold? We don't know what the
threshold is. Nobody will tell us.
And so you get somebody like Carter Page
who
it you know, was doing what he thought
he was supposed to be doing as a, you
know, mid-level Trump campaign person
talking to an Australian ambassador, and
the next thing you know, he knows
Well, he didn't know it actually. The
next thing he is experiencing is he's
under investigation. There are FISA
warrants against him. And then the FISA
warrants were repeatedly renewed
even though there was no evidence that
he that he had ever committed a crime.
I believe, I I many Americans believe
that this was done at the behest of uh
of John Brennan.
And it was all part of Brennan's
plan
to deny Donald Trump the presidency.